http://www.tesselaar.net.au/privacy-policy

Cookies are not enabled.
This site needs to use cookies to function correctly, please enable cookies in your web browser settings (how to enable cookies).
You are using an old web browser that is no longer supported by this website
The site may not work correctly, please upgrade your web browser.
Quick Order
Selected state:
JOIN OUR MAILING LIST
Receive 4 free catalogues throughout the year.
Loading
Please enter email address.
Our catalogue signup system is down. We apologise for the inconvenience.
Money Back GuaranteeIf your plants do not perform, we gladly refund your money, offer you a replacement or credit. You choose the guarantee that best suits you.
Privacy Policy
Tesselaar Privacy Policy
This privacy policy applies to Tesselaar Direct Pty Ltd of 357 Monbulk Road, Silvan, Victoria 3795. ABN 75 411 816 155
Tesselaar Direct Pty Ltd (‘Tesselaar’) respects the privacy of individuals by treating all personal information as confidential and by handling it in accordance with the Privacy Act 1988 and the National Privacy Principles. We respect your right to privacy and understand the need to protect your personal information.
This Privacy Policy sets out how we manage your personal information that we collect about you. It also describes, in general terms, the types of personal information we hold, for what purposes and also sets out how that information is collected, used, stored and disclosed by Tesselaar. Please read this privacy policy before using the website at www.tesselaar.net.au (the “website”) or submitting any personal information.
By using the website, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy. You are encouraged to review the privacy policy whenever you visit the website to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used.
Your personal information is not collected if you only browse this website.
Collection of Your Personal Information
As a retailer of bulbs and plants, during the course of its activities, Tesselaar may collect, use and disclose personal information from:
Customers who use the online shopping facility;
Visitors to and users of our website, including any user forums section of our website;
Customers who enter trade promotions / competitions conducted by Tesselaar;
Customers who register Tesselaar gift card details; and
Customers who call the Tesselaar Customer Service team or otherwise contact us.
This information can be collected:
directly from you;
when you register for catalogues or as a user of the Website;
when you place an order via the Website;
where you access and interact with the website or the customer service team; or
from other sources.
The information collected may include your name, mailing or residential address, telephone number, email address and other transaction and registration details.
Whilst we ask for your Credit Card details at the “Checkout” point, via Phone or Post, we do not store your Credit Card number.  All of our payments are handled by ANZ eGate Internet payment Gateway. Please check the www.anz.com.au and websites for details of their privacy policies and security measures relating to your Credit Card transactions.
USE AND DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
Personal information is used by Tesselaar for its legitimate business purposes, as disclosed at the time of collection. It is also used for ancillary purposes such as locating and identifying customers or otherwise servicing Tesselaar’s relationship with its customers.
Use and Disclosure of Personal Information
You acknowledge and consent that by providing your personal information to us that we may use and disclose your personal information for the purposes for which it was collected or for a related or ancillary purpose such as:
to facilitate and process your order;
to carry out or respond to your requests;
to our third party service providers to assist us in providing and improving our services to you, and to analyse trends in sales and better understand our customer’s needs or to develop, and improve market our products and services to you;
for regulatory reporting and compliance with our legal obligations;
to various regulatory bodies and law enforcement officials and agencies to protect against fraud and for related security purposes;
to our third party service providers to include in a database compiled by us or our third party service provider for use in direct marketing of promotions, product and services we think may interest to you;
to seek your feedback in relation to customer satisfaction and our relationship with you;
Our Use of Cookies
A cookie is a small piece of text that is placed within the memory of a computer and can be later retrieved by web page servers. We use cookies to enhance your interaction and convenience with our website and do not use cookies to record any personal information.
Cookies may record information about your visit, including the type of browser and operating system you use, the previous site you visited, your server’s IP address, the pages you access and the information downloaded by you. While this anonymous statistical data may be aggregated and used in broader statistical analysis by us and our web monitoring service provider to improve our services, at no time can we personally identify you as the source of that data. Your browser may allow you to disable cookies.
ACCURACY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
Tesselaar aims to ensure that all personal information held about you is collected and used in accordance with the National Privacy Principles. If you believe your personal information as held by Tesselaar is not accurate, complete or otherwise requires amendment, please do not hesitate to contact Tesselaar  head office.
PERSONAL INFORMATION SECURITY
We have implemented appropriate physical, electronic and managerial security procedures in order to protect personal information from loss, misuse, alteration or destruction. Access to your personal information is limited to those who specifically need it to conduct their responsibilities.
DESTRUCTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION
Tesselaar providers takes reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify your personal information where it is no longer required and to protect your personal information from unauthorised access, disclosure, loss, misuse and alteration.
ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
Tesselaar will give you access to your personal information which we hold about you. Your right to access your personal information as held by Tesselaar is subject to certain exceptions allowed by law. Your right to access your personal information may be affected by matters such as:
the information being commercially sensitive to Tesselaar or one of its service providers or customers;
posing a threat to life or health of any individual;
access having an unreasonable impact on the privacy of others;
access being unlawful;
access prejudicing enforcement activities relating to criminal conduct or other breaches of law;
a frivolous or vexatious request by you or some other person on your behalf;
the existence of a legal dispute or potential legal dispute; and
denial of access being required or authorized by law.
If Tesselaar denies you access to your personal information, we will provide a reason.
Other than the above, we will not disclose your personal information without your consent unless disclosure is either necessary to prevent a threat to life or health, authorised or required by law, reasonably necessary to enforce the law or necessary to investigate a suspected unlawful activity.
Any permitted handling of personal information under any exemptions under the Act will take priority over this Privacy Policy to the extent of any inconsistency.
Linked Sites
Tesselaar may contain links to websites which are owned or operated by other parties. You should make your own enquiries as to the privacy policies of these parties. We are not responsible for information on, or the privacy practices of, such websites.
Transmission of Your Data
While care is taken to protect your personal information on the website, unfortunately no data transmission over the Internet is guaranteed as 100% secure. Accordingly, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you send to us or receive from us online. This is particularly true for information you send to us via email as we have no way of protecting that information until it reaches us. Once we receive your personal information, we are required to protect it in accordance with the Act.
OPT-OUT IN RESPECT OF PROMOTIONAL MATERIAL
Tesselaar acknowledges and respects its customers’ choice to “opt-out” of direct marketing communication activities undertaken by Tesselaar. If as a customer you not wish to receive promotional material from Tesselaar, please contact Tesselaar  and indicate the particular promotional material you do not wish to receive. All emails, SMS and newsletters from this website allow you to opt-out of further mailings by clicking on the link or responding “unsubscribe”
OBTAINING MORE INFORMATION ABOUT YOUR PRIVACY
More information about your privacy rights, the Act or the National Privacy Principles is available from the Federal Privacy Commissioner’s website at www.privacy.gov.au
RESOLVING YOUR PRIVACY CONCERNS
If you are concerned with the way your personal information has been handled, please contact or write to us, or alternatively, contact Tesselaar as set out below. If your personal information has not been handled in an appropriate way, we will take steps to remedy your concerns in a reasonable time. Any privacy complaint will be handled by Tesselaar in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
Tesselaar Direct Pty Ltd
357 Monbulk Road,
Receive 4 free catalogues throughout the year.
Loading
There was a problem with your request
Please fill out the highlighted fields below.
Our catalogue signup system is down. We apologise for the inconvenience.
More than 75 years experience.
Free Growing Tips with every order.
Tried & Tested bulbs and plants.
Extensive and exclusive range.
Free friendly advice.
Money Back Guarantee
If your plants do not perform, we gladly refund your money, offer you a replacement or credit. You choose the guarantee that best suits you.
$12.50 Guaranteed Delivery
Regardless of the size of your order, postage is a flat $12.50. Your order is guaranteed and insured to arrive safely to you door.
Secure Online Payment
You can buy with confidence on our website knowing your transaction is encrypted and protected by Thawte, the global Security Certificate expert.
There are no products
Subtotal:
